# **Anna Walerys**

# Data Analytics | Digital Marketing | Sales | Project Management

Katonah, NY 10536 | 914 318 8141 | walerysanalytics@gmail.com | walerysan.github.io/ | linkedin.com/in/annawalerys

#### **SUMMARY**

Data analyst with a background in the digital publishing and advertising industry. Experienced in producing and executing content marketing campaigns. Applies analytical and organizational skills to uncover trends and insights to recommend data-driven solutions and guide business decisions. Explores passions for sales and analysis. Pragmatic thinker and practical doer. Motivated and independent learner of new technical skills.

#### **TOOLS**

Tableau
Excel
Python Jupyter Notebook
PostgreSQL
Jira
PowerPoint

#### **SKILLS**

Data-driven Insights
Data Visualizations
Advertising Sales
Digital Marketing
Project Management
English, German, Polish

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Certificate, Data Analytics Program, CareerFoundry, 2021

Certificate, Data Science Practitioner, IBM Skills Academy, 2020

Certificate, Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, IBM Skills Academy, 2020

Scrum Master Workshop, ScrumGoup, Warsaw, Poland, 2017

Postgraduate Studies in Marketing & Management, School of Economics, Warsaw, Poland, 2001

MA in German Studies, University of Szczecin, Poland and University of Augsburg, Germany, 1999

#### PROJECTS:

- Airbnb conducted predictive analytics in Python to derive insights for the travel industry > project details.
- Instacart performed an analysis in Python to uncover customers' behaviors and built their profiles for targeted marketing strategy > project details.
- Rockbuster Stealth explored with SQL the inventory and revenues of a fictive movie rental store to launch an online rental service > project details.
- Influenza examined differences in staffing needs across US states to prepare for the next flu season > project details.

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

### Ringier Axel Springer, Warsaw, Poland

Sales Project Lead @Media Impact, 2017-2018

- Coordinated and executed ad campaigns for short-video formats in social media.
- Doubled the sales through intensive product training of the sales force.
- Collaborated daily with clients and agencies and delivered post-sales reports.
- Streamlined production and execution processes in cooperation with cross-functional teams.
- Prepared multilingual product presentations for internal and external stakeholders.
- Introduced the short-video concept within the international portfolio of the company.

#### Operations Analyst @Media Impact, 2016-2017

- Collected data and analyzed request/delivery workflow of customized ad campaigns within the advertising sales department based on monthly reports generated from Jira and sales CRM.
- Recommended process enhancement based on statistical analysis and reconfigured both, Jira and CRM, applications accordingly.
- Contributed to structural transformations and improved the efficiency of the department.
- Conducted training for sales staff to effectively utilize the redesigned software.
- Reorganized and updated internal website with portfolio for the sales force.

#### Technical Assistant to Editor-in-Chief @Fakt Daily, 2013-2016

- Operated as a link between the newsroom, IT department, and the German-Swiss company owners accommodating the implementation of high-tech solutions in the editorial offices across Poland.
- Performed Polish/German translation duties, including written texts, web content, news articles, live presentations, and internal meetings.

# Guest-Control, Warsaw, Poland (Guest-One in Germany)

#### Operations Lead, Co-Owner, 2010-2014

- Established a Polish branch of a German provider of online guest management tools.
- Designed market-specific digital system features.
- Executed recurring conferences using online registrations and controlled check-ins.
- Delivered event statistics and recommendations for future meetings.